sirsidynix.net 2012-06-26

# Privacy | SirsiDynix.com

### SIRSIDYNIX: PRIVACY POLICY

**Effective date of April 23, 2004**

_This page was last updated June 15, 2010_

Sirsi Corporation, dba SirsiDynix ("SirsiDynix") is committed to protecting your privacy. We recognize your need for protection of any personally identifiable information ("Personal Information") shared with us. SirsiDynix has developed the following Privacy Policy in order to inform you of the care that we place on the protection, management and use of your Personal Information. This Privacy Policy Notice covers the foundation principles of fair information: Awareness, Choice, Notice, Accuracy & Access, Security, Data Integrity, Enforcement, and Oversight.

Personal Information includes information that identifies an individual or institution; for example, a person's name, institution name, mail address, telephone number, e-mail address, or other such information used for contacting or identifying the individual or institution.

In order for SirsiDynix to provide the services or products that you order, Personal Information may be required to fulfill your request. The information you provide to SirsiDynix will be protected in all reasonable means from disclosure to outside parties. SirsiDynix appreciates your trust and provides this privacy policy regarding our practices for managing information. SirsiDynix also has a separate privacy statement that applies to certain personal data that SirsiDynix receives in the United States from the European Union and Switzerland, called the Safe Harbor Privacy Statement.

### DESCRIPTION OF THE ACTIVITIES WHEN PERSONAL INFORMATION IS RECEIVED FROM CLIENT.

We will ask the individual or institution ("Client") when we need Personal Information. Under most circumstances when SirsiDynix requests Personal Information the Client is registering for conferences, surveys, ordering e-mail news or information, joining limited-access sites (such as forum or list servers), signing up for an event or training, or when purchasing and/or registering SirsiDynix products. Personal Information collected by SirsiDynix is often limited to e-mail address, language, country or location, but may include other information when needed to provide a service or product Client requested.

Examples of when Personal Information is requested:

SirsiDynix may collect information about Client's computer hardware and software, if it was not supplied by SirsiDynix. This information may include: Client IP address, browser type, operating system, domain name, access times and referring Web site addresses. This information is used for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of SirsiDynix.

If a Client has selected a service or product that requires payment, we will request Personal Information necessary for billing and/or shipping, such as: name, address, telephone number, and credit card number.

SirsiDynix also collects information about which pages our Clients visit within SirsiDynix. This site visitation data is never linked with Personal Information, except with the user's consent as described below.

You can visit most pages on our site without providing any Personal Information. However, as noted in the examples above, sometimes we do need information to provide the services you request and realize you want the information you provide to SirsiDynix to be protected. SirsiDynix appreciates your trust and offers this privacy statement to inform you of our practices for managing information. Please read the complete SirsiDynix privacy statement herein, and if you choose to provide us with Personal Information, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy Notice.

Personal Information

About Personal Information:

Personal Information will not be sold, leased, or otherwise distributed or disclosed to outside parties unless required by law. All individual information is considered confidential.

Personal Information will not be collected, sold, leased, or otherwise distributed or disclosed for commercial purposes.

Personal Information will not be collected, sold, leased or otherwise distributed or disclosed without notice being given to the individual. At that time, the individual can request the Personal Information not be shared.

Personal Information will not be knowingly collected by SirsiDynix from children.

What information is collected without Client Registration:

The domain name (e.g. [www.SirsiDynix.com](http://www.sirsidynix.com/)) of the visitor.

The IP address of the computer or Internet provider.

The date/time you accessed the site.

How the collected information is used:

Measuring traffic flow and volume.

Diagnosing server problems.

Determining which parts of the site users are visiting.

Delivering services, for example press releases, events information, training or software, which Client requested or purchased.

To notify our users of product upgrades, special offers, updated information and other services.

To allow Client access to limited-entry Websites.

The collected information does not identify individual visitors, unless the individual elects to provide SirsiDynix Personal Information. IP addresses are not linked to any personal identifiers. Statistical information is used only in aggregate (sum total) anonymous form. SirsiDynix uses this data for research purposes only and we may use this information in aggregate anonymous form to create statistical information. In some cases, with Client approval, we will combine site-visitation data with Personal Information in order to provide the Client with personalized content. If Client declines permission, we will not provide Client the personalized service and will not merge Client Personal Information with site-visitation data.

Disclosure of Personal Information

No attempt is made to identify individual users unless illegal behavior is suspected.

Network traffic is monitored to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage to the SirsiDynix's web services.

Personal Information may be disclosed when required to do so by law, or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary when:

It is believed that disclosing the information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating SirsiDynix's Privacy Policy or to protect and defend the rights or property of SirsiDynix and its Web site(s).

To act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of SirsiDynix employees, users of SirsiDynix products or services, or members of the public or when someone may be causing injury to or interfering with SirsiDynix's rights or property, other users, or anyone else who could be harmed by such activities.

To conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on SirsiDynix.

SirsiDynix may occasionally hire or use other parties to provide limited services on our behalf, including packaging, mailing and delivering purchases, answering Client questions about products or services, sending postal mail and processing event registration. We will only provide those companies the information they need to deliver the service, and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose.

Third-party Information

SirsiDynix's Privacy Policy only addresses the use and disclosure of information SirsiDynix collects from a Client.

Any personally identifiable information disclosed to a third party, such as other users or advertisers, is subject to that party's Privacy Policy.

Disclosure of personally identifiable information to third parties, such as other users or advertisers, in general or in chat areas or bulletin boards may result in that information being collected by others and may result in unsolicited messages from others.

SirsiDynix encourages the individual to ask questions and read the third party's Privacy Policy before disclosing personally identifiable information to others.

Cookies

Cookies are temporary files used to store and sometimes track information about a visit to the site, such as an individual's progress, the number of entries in promotions or contests. Cookies also allow access to certain functions, such as the online catalog and electronic resources. SirsiDynix may use cookies to collect information on which newsletter links are clicked by Clients. This information is used to ensure we are sending information Clients want to read. However, it is collected in aggregate form and never linked with the Clients Personal Information.

Cookies do not store any Personal Information, such as e-mail address or individual passwords.

Cookies cannot:

Read other data off an individual's hard drive.

Pass on a virus.

Read cookies created by other sites.

Temporary cookies files are automatically deleted when you close your browser.

Cookies can be "turned off" or disabled by changing the proper setting in your browser.

Changing the browser setting will disable all cookies delivered to your browser not just the ones delivered by SirsiDynix, however Client will not experience a personalized visit nor will Client be able to subscribe to the service offerings on the site.

iBistro/iLink will not operate properly when cookies have been disabled.

Registration

Registration allows an individual to take advantage of some features of SirsiDynix's software, utilize SirsiDynix services and allows SirsiDynix to communicate with you.

Registration will require you to provide various types of information such as your full name, institution name, address, e-mail address, ZIP code, a user name, and password.

Optional information is marked as such.

Providing additional, optional information helps SirsiDynix make its Web site more valuable to the individual.

Whenever an individual provides SirsiDynix with Personal Information, SirsiDynix will make every effort to provide a link to SirsiDynix's Privacy Policy.

Participation in some promotions may not be possible if an individual chooses not to share Personal Information.

SirsiDynix occasionally allows other parties to offer our registered clients information about their products and services. If Client does not want to receive these offers, Client should check the appropriate box.

SirsiDynix may send out periodic e-mails informing the Client of services or security issues related to a product or service the Client requested or licensed. Client will not be able to choose to unsubscribe to these mailings, as they are considered an essential part of the service the Client selected during registration.

Links

SirsiDynix's Web site contains links to other sites.

SirsiDynix is not responsible for the accuracy, currency, and content of any other sites to which SirsiDynix provides hyperlinks or access.

SirsiDynix is not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites.

SirsiDynix cannot be responsible for an individual's privacy when a patron discloses information to outside web sites.

SirsiDynix encourages its Clients to be aware when they leave SirsiDynix's site(s), to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information.

It is the individual's responsibility to protect their Personal Information, including user name and password information.

SirsiDynix's Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by this Web site or SirsiDynix.

Security

Credit card transactions (purchases, etc.) placed on SirsiDynix's site(s) are protected using industry-standard technology to safeguard the confidentiality of the individual information.

This technology includes use of firewalls, secure socket layers (SSL), and/or encryption.

In confirming order statuses, only the last four or five digits of the individual's credit card number is revealed.

In order to further protect individual information, always log out and close the browser when finished using a shared or public computer.

SirsiDynix takes reasonable steps to prevent the introduction of viruses, worms, or other destructive materials.

SirsiDynix cannot guarantee or warrant that materials downloaded from SirsiDynix do not contain viruses, worms, or other destructive materials.

SirsiDynix is not liable for any damages or harm attributable to such materials.

Usage of materials available via download from SirsiDynix is solely at the Client's own risk.

No security system is impenetrable.

SirsiDynix cannot guarantee the absolute security of its database.

SirsiDynix cannot guarantee that the information supplied by the Client will not be intercepted while being transmitted to SirsiDynix over the Internet.

Opt-Out Features

Your information can be reviewed and changed by contacting Client Care.

You may discontinue receiving some of the communications from SirsiDynix, such as e-mail newsletters announcing new features, contests, and new content, by sending an e-mail to [webmaster@SirsiDynix.com](mailto:webmaster@SirsiDynix.com).

You may contact SirsiDynix to opt out of some features and communications by postal mail to:  
Legal Department  
400 West Dynix Drive  
Provo, Utah 84604

An individual can decline to provide SirsiDynix with Personal Information. Please note, in some cases, this will limit your interaction with SirsiDynix.

Policy

General

This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to the terms of SirsiDynix's license agreement and SirsiDynix's support services agreement.

SirsiDynix adheres to the American Library Association's Code of Ethics.

Reference on this Web site to any specific commercial product, process, service, manufacturer, or company does not constitute endorsement or recommendation by SirsiDynix.

Client information will be stored and processed in the United States.

SirsiDynix abides by the safe harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union.

SirsiDynix attempts to abide by all applicable privacy statutes and regulations.

**Notification of Changes**

If SirsiDynix decides to change its Privacy Policy, these changes will be posted to SirsiDynix's Web site in the location you found this current policy.

Patrons will be notified via e-mail so users are always aware of information collected, how it's used, and under what circumstances, if any, the information is disclosed.

Patrons have the ability to opt out of receiving communications from SirsiDynix by editing their account or sending an e-mail to [webmaster@SirsiDynix.com](mailto:webmaster@SirsiDynix.com).

**Enforcement of this Privacy Statement**  
If Client has questions regarding this statement; Client should first contact SirsiDynix by e-mail at [legal@SirsiDynix.com](mailto:legal@SirsiDynix.com). Should you not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or Client inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, Client should then contact the privacy administrator in the Legal Department.

**Contact Information**  
SirsiDynix welcomes Client comments regarding this privacy policy, please contact us by e-mail **at:**  
 **or postal mail at:**  
SirsiDynix Legal Department  
400 West Dynix Drive  
Provo, Utah 84604

### SAFE HARBOR PRIVACY STATEMENT

**SIRSI CORPORATION DBA SIRSIDYNIX**  
This Statement describes how SirsiDynix collects and uses certain personally identifiable information that it receives in the United States from the European Union and Switzerland ("EU and Swiss Personal Data"). In particular, SirsiDynix recognizes that the European Union and Switzerland have established strict protections regarding the handling of EU and Swiss Personal Data, and SirsiDynix therefore has elected to adhere to the US-EU Safe Harbor Privacy Principles and US-Switzerland Safe Harbor Privacy Principles (together, the "Safe Harbors") with respect to such EU and Swiss Personal Data that it receives in the United States. For further background and information about the Safe Harbors, and to see SirsiDynix’s representation on the Safe Harbor List, please refer to the U.S. Department of Commerce's website at [www.export.gov/safeharbor](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor).

**Categories of Individual Data Subjects**

In general, SirsiDynix may obtain EU and Swiss Personal Data in the United States about several different types of individuals, including (i) website visitors, and (ii) clients, suppliers, and business partners, and (iii) SirsiDynix's own employees. SirsiDynix's practices with respect to each of these types of individual data subjects are described below.

**Website Visitors**

SirsiDynix generally collects, uses, and discloses information about website visitors located in the EU or Switzerland in accordance with the Website Privacy Policy at [www.sirsidynix.com/privacy](http://www.sirsidynix.com/privacy).

**Clients, Suppliers, and Business Partners**

SirsiDynix may obtain various types of EU and Swiss Personal Data about patrons of our clients, suppliers, and business partners. Such data may include contact information (names, titles, addresses, phone and fax numbers, and e-mail addresses); information about products and services ordered or provided; financial and payment information; user ID, passwords, and information collected through Internet-based and e-commerce activities, and other transaction-related data.

SirsiDynix may use these types of EU and Swiss Personal Data for business purposes, including to deliver or provide products or services; to trouble-shoot server problems, to establish or maintain client and business relationships; to provide access to Internet-based and e-commerce activities; to perform accounting functions; and to conduct other activities as necessary or appropriate in connection with the servicing and development of the business relationship.

Patrons, employees and agents of our clients, business partners, and suppliers may contact us if any of their EU and Swiss Personal Data changes, or if they would like to access and correct EU and Swiss Personal Data that we maintain about them. Such persons can also contact us by sending an e-mail to the SirsiDynix Legal/Privacy Office, or by using the information at the end of this privacy statement. Also, to the extent that any of these individuals receive marketing communications from SirsiDynix, and wish to unsubscribe or otherwise stop receiving such communications, they can contact us at our website: [webmaster@sirsidynix.com](mailto:webmaster@sirsidynix.com). 

**SirsiDynix Employees**

SirsiDynix employees located in the European Union should consult with their local human resources manager to obtain information about SirsiDynix's practices with respect their EU and Swiss Personal Data. Online job applicants to SirsiDynix should also consult any additional terms that apply when they submit their applications and/or resumes.

**Other Necessary Disclosures**

SirsiDynix may disclose EU and Swiss Personal Data to business partners and subcontractors as necessary in connection with the performance of requested services or solutions, or as otherwise appropriate in connection with a legitimate business need. SirsiDynix may also disclose EU and Swiss Personal Data as necessary in connection with the servicing the software and hardware of the business. In these situations, SirsiDynix will require the recipient of the data to protect the data in accordance with the relevant principles in the Safe Harbors, or otherwise take steps to ensure that the EU and Swiss Personal Data is appropriately protected. SirsiDynix may also disclose EU and Swiss Personal Data where required or permitted by law, or where SirsiDynix believes that such disclosures are appropriate in connection with a law enforcement request.

**Data Security and Integrity**

SirsiDynix has global hosting centers that store and process EU and Swiss Personal Data in locations in the United States, including Utah. SirsiDynix takes reasonable precautions to protect EU and Swiss Personal Data in these centers and in other locations in the United States from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. SirsiDynix also makes reasonable efforts to keep EU and Swiss Personal Data accurate, current, and complete, and reliable for its intended use.

**Dispute Resolution**

SirsiDynix participates in the EU Safe Harbor Privacy Framework as set forth by the United States Department of Commerce. As part of our participation in the safe harbor, we have agreed to TRUSTe dispute resolution for disputes relating to our compliance with the Safe Harbor Privacy Framework. If you have any complaints regarding our compliance with the Safe Harbor you should first contact us (as provided above). If contacting us does not resolve your complaint, you may raise your complaint with TRUSTe by Internet at [http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint&url=fax](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint&url=fax) at415-520-3420, or mail at Watchdog Complaints, TRUSTe, 55 2nd Street, 2nd Floor, San Francisco, CA, USA 94105. If you are faxing or mailing TRUSTe to lodge a complaint, you must include the following information: the name of company, the alleged privacy violation, your contact information, and whether you would like the particulars of your complaint shared with the company. For information about TRUSTe or the operation of TRUSTe's dispute resolution process, see [http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint&url=or](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint&url=or) request this information from TRUSTe at any of the addresses listed above. The TRUSTe dispute resolution process shall be conducted in English. For human resources data we have agreed to cooperate with Data Protection Authorities. 

**Questions**

If you have any questions about this Safe Harbor Privacy Statement, or if you would like to request access to EU and Swiss Personal Data that we may maintain about you, please contact us as follows:

**SirsiDynix**  
Attention: Legal Department / Privacy Office  
400 West Dynix Drive  
Provo, UT 84604  
United States

Toll-free: 800.288.8020  
Phone: 1.801.223.5200  
Fax: 1.801.223.5202  
E-mail: SirsiDynix Legal/Privacy Office

Any questions regarding this Safe Harbor Privacy Statement should first be directed to the SirsiDynix contact above. If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you may then contact the local data protection authorities in your EU member state or Switzerland for further information.
